<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>D2D Natural Resources and Data Literacy</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on D2D Natural Resources and Data Literacy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 13:13:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 13:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the D2D Natural Resources and Data Literacy Project (a part of D2D IFC Program). This website contains information and materials about our capacity building work, focused on training local communities and increasing the transparency in mining sector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mongolian informediaries provided an extremely positive feedback about D2D work</title>
      <link>/2019/06/25/mongolian-informediaries-provided-an-extremely-positive-feedback-about-d2d-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 13:09:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/06/25/mongolian-informediaries-provided-an-extremely-positive-feedback-about-d2d-work/</guid>
      <description>Mongolian participants provided an excellent feedback after participation in the D2D workshop “Natural Resources Data Analytics for Transparency and Stronger Social License”.
D2D asked participants to evaluate the workshop itself, its relevance to the participants’ work, and satisfaction of the chosen tool (Flourish). Not surprisingly, the team received very positive results, where the majority of participants expressed very satisfaction as “Very satisfied” or “Satisfied”.
In addition, the team received several oral requests to organize more similar events in future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2nd D2D Working Group Meeting in Mongolia</title>
      <link>/2019/06/07/2nd-d2d-working-group-meeting-in-mongolia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 13:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/06/07/2nd-d2d-working-group-meeting-in-mongolia/</guid>
      <description>On June 7, 2019 the D2D team in Mongolia organized the second meeting of the D2D Natural Resource Data for Development Working Group.
Participants:
Representatives of the Ministry of Mining and Heavy Industry, Ministry of Finance, Ministry of Environment and Tourism, Mongolian National Mining Association, National Resources Governance Institute, Business Council of Mongolia, EITI Mongolia Secretariat, National University of Mongolia attended the event and provided their insights about improving the open data management processes and overcoming challenges in this field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Water and mining industry round table organized in Mongolia</title>
      <link>/2019/06/06/water-and-mining-industry-round-table-organized-in-mongolia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 13:08:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/06/06/water-and-mining-industry-round-table-organized-in-mongolia/</guid>
      <description>On June 6, 2019 the D2D team in Mongolia organized the traditional water and mining industry round table, inviting representatives and the senior management of the biggest mining companies and government agencies.
Oleksiy Anokhin presented insights from the EITI datasets, which boosted an active discussion among participants.
Add 1 picture from the event here and more to the gallery tab
Add more information about this event</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D2D held a capacity building training for infomediaries in Mongolia</title>
      <link>/2019/06/05/d2d-held-a-capacity-building-training-for-infomediaries-in-mongolia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 13:18:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/06/05/d2d-held-a-capacity-building-training-for-infomediaries-in-mongolia/</guid>
      <description>On June 4-5, 2019 D2D team organized a capacity building training for informediaries (local journalists, representatives of mining companies, students, academia, members or local government) in Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia. During two days the participants focused their efforts on working with open data about natural resources and water in Monglolia, crafting own stories and presenting them to colleagues.
Several guest speakers provided their insights about the discussed topics:
Mr. Shar Tsolmon: Coordinator of EITI National Secretariat</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D2D co-organized an Open Data Hackathon in Mongolia</title>
      <link>/2019/03/25/d2d-co-organized-an-open-data-hackathon-in-mongolia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 13:15:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/03/25/d2d-co-organized-an-open-data-hackathon-in-mongolia/</guid>
      <description>To engage new people and draw their attention to the available mining open data, the D2D program supported and co-organized (together with with DW Akademie, Deutsche Welle’s center of excellence for training and knowledge transfer, the Mongolian Center for Investigative Reporters, the Press Institute of Mongolia, the National Statistical Office and Innovation Hub) the first Mongolian Data Journalism Hackathon #HackInequality on March 23-24, 2019, which sparked a significant interest among local media, journalists, graphic designers, and analysts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mongolian youth participated in a data analytics workshop</title>
      <link>/2018/10/08/mongolian-youth-participated-in-a-data-analytics-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 13:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/08/mongolian-youth-participated-in-a-data-analytics-workshop/</guid>
      <description>On October 10, 2018 the D2D team organized a workshop in Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia for local youth, where participants had a chance to explore open data related to natural resources, finance, and water in Mongolia.About 40 young Mongolians created 7 teams and learned how to work with open data and extract insights from it. They learned how to find and clean open data, explored the best data visualization practices, and storytelling techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>/2014/06/06/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2014 13:08:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/06/06/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the D2D Natural Resources and Data Literacy Project (a part of D2D IFC Program). This website contains information and materials about our capacity building work, focused on training local communities and increasing the transparency in mining sector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the D2D Natural Resources and Data Literacy project page.
We developed this web-site to summarize all information and materials about the D2D work for your convenience.The project contains open data about natural resources and different deliverables (links, posts, pictures, videos, presentations etc).
Let us briefly introduce the D2D program to you:
Program objectives: to improve utility of natural resource industry data for the development impact
Structure: joint WB/IFC program led by IFC</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>If you have any questions or suggestions, please contact us via oanokhin@ifc.org
To be updated</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Countries</title>
      <link>/countries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/countries/</guid>
      <description>Currently D2D operates in four countries - Colombia, Ghana, Mongolia, and Peru (Phase II of the program).
Phase II will have two more countries - Guinea and Sierra Leone.
To be updated</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data</title>
      <link>/data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data/</guid>
      <description>This tab will contain open data about natural resources, water, and revenue sharing information.
The data will be presented in the format of links to specific datasets, refined by D2D team, or links to specific sources, where the original data can be downloaded.
To be updated</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links</title>
      <link>/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/links/</guid>
      <description>This tab summarizes all links, presented on this web-site together. Additionally, some links are duplicated under different tabs to make your access to this information more convenient.
To be updated</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media</title>
      <link>/media/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/media/</guid>
      <description>This tab summarizes official press-releases about the D2D program.
TBD. To be updated</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Partners</title>
      <link>/partners/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/partners/</guid>
      <description>D2D work would not be possible without multiple fantastic partners of our team in different countries:
Ghana:
MESTMongolia:
National Statistical Office of Mongolia
Press Institutte of Mongolia
Mongolian Center for Investigative Reporters (MCIR)
Hub Innovation Center
To be updated</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photos</title>
      <link>/photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/photos/</guid>
      <description>This tab contains links to some photos, taken during different workshops and other events.
1. Mining Open Data for Solving Development Challenges
Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia (October 10, 2019)
Photos
2. HackInequality. The First Mongolian Open Data Hackathon
Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia (March 23-24, 2019)
Photos
3. Natural Resources Data Analytics for Transparency and Stronger Social License
Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia (June 4-5, 2019)
Photos
To be updated</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentations</title>
      <link>/presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/presentations/</guid>
      <description>This tab will contain links to some D2D presentaions, prepared for our trainings and events.
To be updated</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentations</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>TBD. To be updated</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team</title>
      <link>/team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/team/</guid>
      <description>The core team of the project:
Alla Morrison (Program Manager)
Michelle Jacome (Operations Officer)
LinkedIn
Delgermaa Boldbaatar (D2D Program Mongolia Coordinator)
LinkedIn
Oleksiy Anokhin (Consultant)
LinkedIn, Twitter
Team will be updated. Photos will be updated</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools</title>
      <link>/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tools/</guid>
      <description>In our capacity building work we teach and use multiple tools:
Flourish, new platform for visualizing, presenting and telling stories with data.Currently Flourish partners with Google News Lab to make Floursh available for journalists. Floursih is available among Google News Initiative tools.In our opinion, Flourish is easy to pick, intuitive, beautiful, and free - a perfect combination for teaching local communities new data literacy skills.
R - a programming language and free software environment for statistical computing and graphics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter</title>
      <link>/twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/twitter/</guid>
      <description>TBD. To be updated</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video</title>
      <link>/video/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/video/</guid>
      <description>This tab will summarize links for video products, created by D2D workshops’ participants and media.
To be updated</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>